恶魔城
第四季 第３集
‎谁是美人呢
Who's a pretty girl, then?
‎谁是美人
Who's a pretty girl?
‎没错
That's right.
‎就是你
You are.
‎你看什么呢
What are you looking at?
‎他告诉我们把财物藏在这里
He told us to place possessions
‎以便日后需要的时候好找
to aid later identification if need be.
‎我要看看是否管用
I needed to see if it still worked.
‎我要去见艾萨克
I'm going to see Isaac.
‎不
No!
‎我不会带它去
I'm not taking it with me.
‎我可以问你个问题吗
May I ask you a question?
‎当然可以
Of course.
‎我们在这里干什么
What are we doing here?
‎这问题太宽泛了
That is a very broad question.
‎说得具体点
Be more specific.
‎坐下
Sit.
‎我不必向你解释
I do not need to tell you
‎黑暗生物是什么样的 锻造师
what night creatures are, forgemaster.
‎叫我艾萨克就行
You can call me Isaac.
‎你要吃个浆果吗
Would you like a berry?
‎这就是个例子
Case in point.
‎我是黑暗生物
I am a night creature.
‎我吃肉喝血
I eat blood and meat.
‎吃个浆果也许不会要你的命
A berry would probably not kill you.
‎黑暗生物杀戮
Night creatures kill,
‎毁灭和掠夺
destroy and despoil.
‎这是我们的荣幸
It is our pleasure.
‎黑暗生物要服从锻造师的意志
Night creatures do the will of their forgemasters.
‎那么也许 ‎我根本不了解你的意志
Then perhaps I simply don't understand your will.
‎你让我们把人埋起来
You have us burying people.
‎这座城里遍地都是死人
The city was littered with dead.
‎太多人腐烂得厉害
Too many of them were too decayed
无法用魔法转化
to be converted by magic.
‎所以呢
So?
‎所以要埋葬他们
So they need to be buried.
‎你不是傻瓜
You are not a fool.
‎会有昆虫和疾病滋生
Insects and diseases would breed.
‎我提醒你 这里所有人都是受害者
And I would remind you that everyone here was a victim.
‎他们应该被安葬
They deserve a burial.
‎那为什么我们
Then why do we care
‎要操心昆虫和疾病呢
about insects and diseases?
‎想问就问吧
Ask your question.
‎我们杀戮 毁灭和掠夺
We kill, destroy and despoil.
‎你却让我们埋葬腐烂的死人
You have us burying the rotten dead
‎重建和修复这个地方
and rebuilding and repairing this place.
‎你为什么要让我们违背自己的本性
Why do you have us going against our nature?
‎你们的本性易变
Your nature is fluid.
‎你相信自己是毁灭的工具
You believe you are tools of destruction
‎只因为你的同胞一直被这样利用
only because this is how your kind have always been used.
‎吃个浆果吧
Have a berry.
‎回忆起来了
Memories.
‎这不是血 也不是肉
It's not blood or meat,
‎但你吃了似乎也没有丧命
but you don't appear to have died from it.
‎我来回答你的问题
I'll answer your question.
‎这个城市曾经居住着成千上百人
This city was once home to many hundreds of people,
‎也许还有更多人
perhaps more.
‎等到尸体被掩埋
It could be resettled,
‎废墟被处理 建筑被修复
once the bodies are buried,
‎人们就可以重新在此定居
the debris is disposed of and the structures are repaired.
‎我们很快就要走了
We will be moving on soon.
‎等我们走了之后
After we are gone,
‎这座城市将留下来
the city will be here for people to find
‎人们会找到这里安家
and make homes in.
‎你想再吃个浆果吗
Would you like another berry?
‎好吧
I think so.
‎吃一个吧
Take one.
‎你看 你可以用锤子盖房子
You see, you can use a hammer to build a house
‎也可以敲碎头骨
or crack a skull.
‎你作为工具重返人间
You are returned to earth as tools,
‎我会按我的想法使用工具
and I will use tools as I wish.
‎有好多回忆
So many memories.
‎我最终也可以选择
I can also choose, in the end,
‎承认你根本不是工具
to recognize that you are not tools at all.
‎因为没有工具尝到浆果
For no tool would taste a berry
‎还会记得前世
and remember the time in its first life
吃到浆果的时光
when it encountered them.
‎但我们是来自地狱的生物...
But we are creatures of hell...
‎奉命去战斗
to be commanded to fight.
‎总有一天 地狱会空荡荡
One day, hell will be emptied
‎地狱之门会在风中作响
and its doors will rattle in the wind.
‎什么
What?
‎借着我的手
Through my hand,
‎上帝以他的怜悯 ‎从地狱中解救被诅咒的人
God lifts the damned from hell in his mercy
‎成为我的士兵 在人间赎罪
to enact their penance on the Earth as my soldiers.
-‎是的  -‎他们在人间的赎罪
- Yes. - Should their penance on Earth
‎也应该永恒不变吗
be eternal too?
‎我...
I...
‎不清楚
do not know.
‎我也不清楚
Neither do I.
‎我们应该一起弄清楚
We should find out together.
‎在此期间
In the meantime,
‎我们可以做的事情
we can both do a little more
‎比我们想要做的多一些
than what we were intended for.
‎我能说句话吗
May I make an observation?
‎说吧
You may.
‎你变了
You are changing.
‎我觉得你还想复仇
There is still revenge in you, I think.
‎但也有其他想法
But other things, too.
‎也许吧
Perhaps.
‎我们还要战斗吗 艾萨克
Are we still fighting, Isaac?
‎我们总是有战斗的理由
We're always fighting for something.
‎但我明白你的意思
But I take your meaning.
‎快了
Soon.
‎他也许说得有道理
He might have a point.
‎你觉得呢
What do you think?
‎我花了几周时间
It took me a few weeks
‎转化这座城市中能用的尸体
to transform the viable bodies in the city.
‎又花了几周时间完成修复 并埋葬那些
Weeks more to effect repairs and bury those
损坏得无法转化的尸体
too destroyed to convert.
‎我抽出时间想一想
Is it so bad to take my time
这有什么不好
and think for a moment?
‎是我变了吗
Have I changed?
‎说吧 说点什么
Go on, say something.
‎我杀了你 老巫师
I killed you, old wizard.
‎你肯定对这事有意见
You must have an opinion on that.
‎没有吗
No?
‎我杀过很多人 老巫师 原因有很多
I have killed many people, old wizard, for many reasons.
‎但杀你只是凭感觉
But killing you felt just.
‎感觉像是一点点修复这个世界
It felt like repairing the world a little.
‎我喜欢那种感觉
I liked that feeling.
‎很长一段时间
For a long time,
‎我满足于做别人手里的刀
I was content to be the knife that others wielded.
不过最近 ‎老巫师
But lately, old wizard,
‎我觉得自己更像是手 而不是刀
I have felt more like the hand than the knife.
‎我这辈子都被动应对
My whole life, I have reacted to things.
‎很少主动出击
Rarely acted.
‎所以 ‎是的
So, yes,
我变了
I have changed.
‎我能控制这个世界
I have agency in this world.
‎我能创造未来
I can create futures.
‎幸好 我可以创造未来
And, happily, I could create a future
‎同时终结你们的未来
and end yours at the same time.
‎上帝是仁慈的
God is good.
‎我不知道接下来会做什么
I wonder what I will do next.
‎镜子
Mirror.
‎这是什么
What is this?
‎镜子先生
Sir Mirror.
‎你要做什么
What are you doing?
‎你是哪位
And who might you be?
‎你不记得我了吗
Do you not remember me?
‎你看起来不容易被人记住
You do not look memorable.
‎瓦尼
Varney.
‎德古拉伯爵原来的手下瓦尼
Varney of Dracula's original cohort.
‎我在战争初期去了塔哥维斯特
I left for Targoviste early in the campaign.
‎你为什么要连接到我的镜子 瓦尼
Why are you connecting to my mirror, Varney?
‎那个标出你在各地行踪的人
I have spoken with people who marked your passage
‎跟我谈过了
across the land.
‎你做得很不错 先生
You have done great work, sir.
‎你还没回答我的问题
My question is pending.
‎锻造师艾萨克
I am working to bring about
‎我在努力让德古拉起死回生
Dracula's return from the dead, Isaac Forgemaster.
‎真有意思
How very interesting.
‎不止如此
It's more than that.
‎我一直在和各地的魔法师
I've been speaking with magicians and scholars
‎和学者们交谈
across the land.
‎有吸血鬼 也有人类
Both vampire and human.
‎一起努力搜集古老的魔咒和知识
Working together to collect ancient spells and lore.
‎设计出一套方法
Constructing a system
‎从地狱中救出德古拉伯爵
with which to pluck Dracula from hell
‎让他重掌天下大权
and reinstall him in the world with power.
‎那又会怎样
To what end?
‎他还有未尽的事业 先生
He has unfinished business, sir.
‎他欠我们的是死亡
He owes us death.
‎数量空前的死亡
Death in volumes unprecedented.
‎他的伟大事业还没有完成
His great work remains incomplete.
‎我也有未尽的事业 瓦尼
So does mine, Varney.
‎你的事业难道像
Well, is yours as important
‎灭绝杀死他妻子的种族一样重要吗
as the extinction of the race that killed his wife?
‎你自己都讨厌的种族
The race that you yourself hate?
‎对我来说很重要
It is to me.
‎我们拭目以待吧
Afterwards, we will see.
‎我对德古拉最喜爱的锻造师期望过高了
I expected better than that of Dracula's favored forgemaster.
‎等到太阳升起
Then, come daylight,
‎你就会在你的棺材里失望地打滚
you can wriggle in your little coffin with disappointment.
‎但是不要吵闹 ‎因为我完成自己的使命前
But do it quietly, as I do not wish to hear your voice again
‎不想再听到你的声音
until my own task is complete.
‎镜子先生
Sir Mirror,
别再让这个人召唤我了
do not allow this one to call me again,
‎去睡吧
and go to sleep.
‎去你的…
Fuck you...
‎他不听我说完
Ugh! He cut me off!
‎我觉得你让他烦透了
I think you bored him.
‎他不知道我是谁吗
Doesn't he know who I am?
‎哦 拜托
Oh, for God's sake.
‎我是瓦尼 伦敦的瓦尼 ‎从伦敦建成以来
I'm Varney. Varney of London. Since before it was London.
‎伦敦还是罗马鬼城时 我就很强大
I was mighty when London was a Roman ghost town
‎我们还用人头骨来标记我们的边界
and we still marked our borders out with human skulls.
‎他去死吧
Fuck him.
没有他 我们自己干
We'll do it without him.
‎我改变主意了
I changed my mind.
‎让士兵用床抬着我在乡间游走
Have soldiers carry me around the countryside on a bed.
‎我在开玩笑
I was making a joke.
‎我不在乎 去做吧
I don't care. Do it.
‎浑身都疼
Everything hurts.
‎好吧 也没那么糟
Well, this isn't so bad.
‎我们在这里待了几周了
We've been out here for weeks.
‎我不想知道还能有多糟
I don't want to know how it can get worse.
‎-那么…  ‎-我说过 我不想知道
- Well, it... - I said I don't want to know.
‎我不想再听你讲什么
I don't want to hear any more of your stories
‎马鞍疮和吃老鼠的故事了
about saddle boils and eating rats.
‎好吧 但我跟你说过 ‎我看到
All right, all right, but did I tell you about the time
18只松鼠杀一条狗的故事吗
I saw 18 squirrels murder a dog?
闭嘴
Stop.
‎看在上帝的份上 闭嘴吧
In the name of God, stop.
‎给你 喝了就不疼了
Here. Dull the pain.
‎这样不对
This is all wrong.
‎我爱你 但说真的
I love you, but, really,
‎我准备送你坐上马车回家
I'm ready to put you on a wagon home.
‎不
No.
‎这种情形
This.
‎我们到处奔走...
We've been touring...
现在还没走完卡米拉标记的领土
Not even the entire territory Camilla marked out,
‎只完成了一小部分
just a piece of it.
...都几周了
...for weeks.
‎这样不对
And this is all wrong.
‎好了
All right.
‎女人 解释一下
Explain yourself, woman.
‎我不是特别喜欢人类
I have no particular love for humans.
‎我们位于食物链的顶端
There's a food chain, and we're on top.
‎人类不过是穿鞋的猪
Humans are pigs with shoes,
‎他们想吃培根的时候 不会掉眼泪
and they don't cry when they want bacon.
‎我把人类变成食物 也不会难过
I am not sad when I turn humans into food.
‎明白吗
Understood?
‎有话直说 莫拉娜
Spit it out, Morana.
‎有什么想法直接说出来
Directly say what you're thinking,
‎不然你会感到困扰
or you'll tie yourself up in knots.
‎天啊
God.
我和你在一起生活太久了
I have lived with you for too long.
‎好吧 有没有迅速而仁慈的方法
Okay, is there a swift and merciful way
‎让我们控制从城堡到大海之间
for us to take control of all the designated territory
‎所有划定的领土
between the castle and the sea?
‎你是说 打个响指就搞定吗
You mean, snap my fingers and it's all done?
‎不 当然没有
No, of course not.
‎当然没有
Of course not.
‎这会是逐步推进的硬仗 对吗
It will be hard-fought, mile by mile, right?
‎好吧 别说得那么露骨
Well, let's not make it sound desperate.
‎但这绝不简单
But it won't be simple.
‎不是
No.
‎也会有苦难
There will be suffering.
‎这是战争 莫拉娜 总是会有苦难
It's war, Morana. There's always suffering.
‎这不是战争
It's not war.
‎没有对战的双方
There are no two sides to this.
‎这是步步紧逼的进攻
It's a rolling invasion
‎对几十万人的诱捕
and entrapment of hundreds of thousands of humans.
‎不幸的是 人类比猪聪明
Humans who are, sadly, cleverer than pigs
‎他们会战斗 痛苦 恐惧和逃跑
and will fight and suffer and fear and run.
‎那我换个说法
Then I choose a different word.
‎这是"战役"
It's "battle."
‎我跟你来到这里
I came out here with you
因为我想亲眼看看
because I wanted to see for myself
‎这个计划有什么后勤困难
the logistical challenges to the plan.
‎我跟你说了 你不用非得来
And I told you, you didn't have to.
‎我会视察战场
I'd survey the theater of combat
告诉你我需要什么
and let you know what I needed.
‎还有...
Also...
‎你问过我
you're the one who asked me
是否想指挥一个帝国
if I wanted to command an empire.
‎是的 我知道
Yes. I know.
‎在家里就更能理解了
It made a lot more sense back home.
‎专心点 莫拉娜
Focus, Morana.
‎别因为我不是军人就教训我
Don't talk down to me because I am not a soldier.
‎这将是可怕的烂摊子
This is going to be a horrifying mess
‎我们有生之年都要收拾这个烂摊子
that we will be dealing with till the end of our days,
‎这场战争将造成 ‎历史上前所未有的苦难
and it will cause more suffering than history has yet seen!
‎别因为我是军人就对我摆架子
Don't condescend to me because I am a soldier.
‎我能打赢战争
I win wars.
‎过了这么长时间 你突然质疑我
Are you suddenly doubting me after all this time,
‎是否因为你过我的生活累得腿疼
because your legs are sore from living my life?
‎你准备在下半辈子‎一次又一次
Are you ready to fight the same war over and over again
打同样的战争吗
for the rest of your life?
‎你想知道我的想法吗
You want to know what I think?
‎洗耳恭听
Always.
‎我想 无论取得什么成就
I think that whatever we achieve,
‎我们都要一起实现
we achieve it together.
‎就你和我
You and me.
‎卡米拉抛出疯狂的计划
Carmilla throws a crazy plan at us,
‎我们来推行这个计划
and it's us who make it work.
‎换句话说
Or, put another way,
‎尽管有卡米拉 还是我们来实施计划
we make it work despite Carmilla.
‎丽诺尔从来都帮不上忙
And Lenore's never any bloody help.
她大部分时间都有点怪
She's off with the fairies most of the time.
‎只有我们
It's us.
在家的时候‎更能理解这个疯狂的计划
And the crazy plan makes sense back home because,
‎我也不清楚
I don't know,
‎因为卡米拉有扭曲现实的魔法
Carmilla has this magic reality distortion spell,
‎我们为自己能实施计划感到骄傲
and we pride ourselves on making things work.
‎但我们在这里待了几周 ‎
But we've been out here for weeks,
‎远离卡米拉和她的疯狂 我要跟你说…
away from her and her madness, and I'm telling you...
‎怎么回事
What's happening?
‎有人偷袭
It's an attack.
‎黎明时分
At dawn.
‎他们知道我们的身份
They know what we are.
‎显然他们不傻
And apparently they're not stupid.
我要用我的箱子
I need to get to my trunk.
‎那个箱子吗
That one?
‎你从来没打开过
You never open that.
里面是什么
What's in it?
‎白昼盔甲
Day armor.
‎躲进箱子里
Get in the trunk.
‎不
No.
‎箭射不进去 光也照不进去
Arrows can't pierce it and light can't get in.
‎躲进该死的箱子里 亲爱的
Get in the damn trunk, love.
‎快点
Come on!
‎烧死他们
Burn them alive!
‎好了
Right.
‎来吧
Come on!
‎叫他们出来
Bring them out!
‎过来吧 狗杂种
Over here, dogfuckers!
‎这就对了
That's right!
‎该死的傻畜生
Idiot fucking livestock.
施第里尔的士兵
Soldiers of Styria!
‎穿上盔甲遮住皮肤
Armor up and cover your skin!
看来我们赢了
I take it we won.
‎是的
Yes.
‎很好 我想亲手杀了你
Good. I want to kill you myself.
‎你知道这个箱子有多难闻吗
Do you know what this thing smells like?
‎他们不是战士
They weren't fighters.
‎他们只是普通人
They were just people.
‎村民
Villagers.
‎农民什么的
Farmers and the like.
‎我不想反驳你对卡米拉的看法
I don't disagree with what you said about Carmilla.
‎她是我的好朋友
She's my dear friend,
‎但我们都知道她是什么人
but we both know what she's like.
‎我的确不同意打这场仗
I did disagree about the war.
‎只要我投入战斗 ‎就没有我打不赢的战役
There's no battle I can't win when I put my back into it
‎我身边有你和你的头脑
and I have you and your mind beside me.
‎但...
But...
我刚刚击退了该死的农民
I just fought fucking farmers.
‎看到他们眼中的恐惧
Saw the fear in their eyes.
‎不是害怕去死
Not fear of dying.
‎而是害怕没有打过仗
Fear of not having fought.
‎害怕救不了他们的族人
Fear of not saving their people.
‎我们待在该死的田野中
And we're in the middle of a fucking field.
‎无可救药的战场
A hopeless battle theater.
‎除了这片土地‎什么都没有
Except this whole land
只有田野和森林
is nothing but fields and forests.
‎但他们还是投身战斗
But they did it anyway.
‎我们永远停不下来 对吧
We'd never stop, would we?
‎胜利的条件就是不停地战斗
Victory condition is just fighting and holding
‎维持她整个疯狂的帝国架构
the whole insane structure of her empire together
‎直到我老死
until I die of old age.
‎我希望我是错的
I want to be wrong.
‎我希望你是错的
I want you to be wrong.
‎-我们能做到  -‎我们能做到
- We could do it. - We could.
但我们要永远这样做
But we'd be doing it forever.
‎你要永远在这里战斗
You'd be out here fighting forever.
‎我会回到施第里尔
I'd be back at Styria
‎永远努力保持供应线的顺畅
trying to keep supply lines intact forever.
‎我们再也不会见面
And we'd never see each other again.
‎对不起
I am sorry.
‎我希望我是错的
I want to be wrong.
‎我们在白昼的冷光里 哼
We're in the cold light of day, ha!
‎而卡米拉的宏大计划…
And Carmilla's grand plan...
‎人类要为自己在世上的地位而战
The humans are going to fight for their place in the world.
‎总是如此
Constantly.
‎在白昼的冷光里
In the cold light of day,
我要问自己
I have to ask myself this.
‎我想这样吗
Do I want this?
‎如果我们...
Do we want this...
可以一起做其他事 ‎我们还想这样吗
when we can do so much else together?
‎姐妹们
Sisters.
‎赫克托终于准备好
Hector is finally ready
‎开始制造黑暗生物了
to start making night creatures.
‎回家吧 ‎要开始了
Come home. It begins.
‎比我想象的还要糟糕
It's worse than I could have imagined.
‎我这辈子见过不少破败的城镇
And I've seen more than a few wrecked towns in my life.
‎我不明白的是...
What I don't understand is...
‎德古拉先袭击这里 ‎因为他妻子死在这儿 对吗
Dracula hit it first, when his wife died here, right?
‎但这里到处是吸血鬼和黑暗生物
But it's still infested with vampires and night creatures.
‎他们的最终目的是什么
What's their endgame here, hm?
‎他们能得到什么
What do they get?
‎这些人根本没机会恢复和重建
These people never had a chance to recover and rebuild.
‎太可怕了
It's awful.
‎一切都把我们引到这里
And everything has led us here.
‎也就是说 我们来这里是有原因的
Which means we are here for a reason.
‎不知道我们怎么融入这座城市
Not sure how we fit into this.
‎融入
Fit.
‎嗯
Hm.
‎等等
Hold on.
‎这是什么东西
What is that thing?
‎可能不是我想的那样 但…
Well, it can't be what I think it is, but...
‎你们来了
Ah, there you are.
‎好好看了我们漂亮的城市吗
Getting a good look at our fine city?
‎我宁愿好好看看你的地下宫廷
I'd rather get a good look at your Underground Court.
‎还不行
Not yet.
我想先确定可以相信你们
I want to be certain you can be trusted first.
‎太好了 因为我们想先确定
That's good, because we want to make sure
‎我们可以相信你
we can trust you first.
‎你忘了在跟谁说话
You forget who you're speaking to.
‎我们需要时间到处看看
We'd like some time to look around.
‎我相信你稍后能再找到我们
You can find us again later, I'm sure.
‎但我们有重要的事情要讨论
But we have important matters to discuss.
‎拯救城市 恢复王位
Saving the city. Restoring the throne.
‎发布命令
Imposing order.
‎我们也有很重要的事情要谈
We have important matters to discuss too.
‎在此期间 我们要看看
In the meantime, we're going to take a good long look
‎你到现在都没能做到的事情
at how you've failed to do any of that so far.
‎以及我们是否选择帮助你
And whether we're going to choose to help you.
‎她确实需要我们的帮助
She does need our help.
‎但我厌倦了在别人的故事里客串
But I am sick of being a bit player in someone else's story.
‎走吧
Walk away.